Ernst Bacon Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Ernst Bacon Collection1907-1990 (bulk 1930-1980)
ML31.B23
Bacon, Ernst, 1898-1990
around 6,000 items 54 boxes 16 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Ernst Bacon was an American composer, pianist, and conductor. The collection contains music, writings, correspondence, iconography, programs, clippings, publicity materials, and other miscellaneous items.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Bacon, Ernst, 1898-1990--Autographs.; Bacon, Ernst, 1898-1990--Correspondence.; Bacon, Ernst, 1898-1990--Portraits.; Bacon, Ernst, 1898-1990.; Bacon, Ernst, 1898-1990.; Bloch, Ernest, 1880-1959--Correspondence.; Chadwick, G. W. (George Whitefield), 1854-1931--Correspondence.; Persichetti, Vincent, 1915-1987--Correspondence.; Sandburg, Carl, 1878-1967--Correspondence.; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975--Correspondence.
Titles
Bacon collection, 1907-1990
Administrative Information
Provenance
30 mss. Deposit; Ernst Bacon; Nov. 1983.
Bulk of material Bequest; Ernst Bacon; 1991.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Access and Restrictions
The Ernst Bacon Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Performing Arts Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use. Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Sketch
Ernst Bacon, composer, pianist, and conductor was born on May 26, 1898. He was the son of Dr. Charles S. Bacon and Maria von Rosthorn Bacon, herself a Viennese-trained musician. He studied at Northwestern University, the University of Chicago, and the University of California, also privately with Alexander Raab, Glenn Dillard Gunn, Ernest Bloch, and Karl Weigl. Among the numerous awards and grants he received are the Bispham Award, the Ditson and the League of Composers Commission, the Pulitzer fellowship, a Guggenheim fellowship, and grants from the National Institute of Arts and Letters, American Society of Authors, Composers, and Publishers, and The National Endowment for the Arts. A multi-faceted musician, Bacon composed and conducted symphonies, operas, piano concertos, musical theater, ensemble and solo instrumental and vocal works. In addition, he concertized as a pianist in Europe and America, and he conducted the WPA orchestra in California from 1935 to 1937. He taught and administered at Eastman School of Music of the University of Rochester(1926-27), Syracuse University's music department (1945-47), and Converse College in South Carolina (1938-45). He distinguished himself as a writer with such works as Notes on the Piano, The Honor of Music, and Words on Music. In Our Musical Idioms Bacon presented a new theory of scale models derived from diatonic scales. He was also music critic for "The Argonaut," the weekly publication of Converse College. Ernst Bacon was respected as a philosopher by close circle of friends who were fortunate enough to get to see his unpublished writings, [i.e. Imaginary Dialogues and his many poems]. He was a highly opinionated man, a fact which can be witnessed by the large volume of letters to the editor written to several major and not so major serials.
Paul Horgan, one of Ernst Bacon's close friends and his sometime collaborator, summarized Ernst Bacon by writing: "...his wonderful variousness of gifts all gather at the center in the name of the art inherent in mankind. With him, to see deeply is to see in a wide-angled vision; and to create is for him to release his full richness of nature in all his work. ...If there is no Grand Duke of Weimar now available to give his genius full patronage and opportunity, I think we may, even as we deplore the lack of comforting recognitions and rewards commensurate with his achievement, safely leave the future the proper recognition of Ernst Bacon as a great man and a great artist."
Bacon was a devoted family man. He married four times and had six children. Ernst Bacon died on March 16, 1990 in Orinda, California.
Scope and Content Note
Materials in the Ernst Bacon Collection span his entire ninety-one year life. They include five series: Music, Writings, Correspondence, Iconography, and Miscellaneous materials. The bulk of materials are found in the Music, Correspondence, and Writings series.
The Music Series contains holographs, copyist manuscripts, and photoduplications of Ernst Bacon's music. Among these are his manuscripts for songs, solo instrumental pieces, and small ensembles with or without voice or voices. There is also a section of untitled holographs and photocopies of sketches and music workbooks with holographic annotation. Works are arranged alphabetically by title and cross-referenced when appropriate. There are also 30 pages of undeveloped titles sketches, which come from what Ernst Bacon called his woodpile, these have been alphabetized and foldered together.
The Writings Series consists of two subseries, poetry and prose. Both subseries contain published and unpublished works written by Ernst Bacon and arranged alphabetically by title. Included among the Prose subseries are many of his letters to various editors. These are included here because of the highly expository nature of the writing, which is more like prose than typical correspondence. The Collection also contains many notebooks which Bacon used for his prose writings. Although music is not the main emphasis of these materials, there are some musical jottings.
The Correspondence Series, is divided into two subseries, Family and General. The Family Correspondence Subseries contains all correspondence received by Ernst Bacon from his family. It also includes letters written by Ernst Bacon to family members. All correspondence files are arranged alphabetically by author and in chronological order therein. All correspondence written to family members by Ernst Bacon is filed under the addressee in chronological order, with the exception of the correspondence of Ellen, Peggy, and Paul Bacon. Letters of Ellen or Peggy to Ernst Bacon have been separated from letters of Ernst Bacon to them and then filed chronologically. Letters of Ernst Bacon's son, Paul, includes materials from and about his estate.
The bulk of the correspondence is found in the General Correspondence Subseries. As mentioned above letters to the editor, which are usually found in this subseries, have been listed in prose subseries of the Writing series for the aformentioned reason. Contained here are letters from notable musicians and writers including Ernest Bloch, G. Whitefield Chadwick, and Vincent Persichetti, Carl Sandburg, and Thornton Wilder; there are also letters from everyone else who were not family.
The Iconography Series contains photographs, artwork, and posters. Among the photographs are portraits of Ernst Bacon alone, Bacon with his father and mother and various family members, etc. Some of the art is in Ernst Bacon's hand. A notable piece of art in the collection is the original caricature of Ernst Bacon by the artist Sotomayor. This series also contains posters advertising performances given by Ernst Bacon from 1918.
The Miscellaneous Series comprises academic material dating from Ernst Bacon's undergraduate years, two appointment books, a Who's Who certificate, clippings from 1920-76, financial/legal papers dating from 1907-77, lists of various kind, some dated and some undated, a radio interview with Ernst Bacon, programs, publicity releases, and writings by others.
Organization of the Ernst Bacon Collection
The Ernst Bacon Collection is organized in five series:
Music
Writings
Correspondence
Iconography
Miscellaneous
http://lccn.loc.gov/2003561021
Container List
- Music, 1898-1990 (Box 1-27)
  Consists of holographs, copyist ms., printed music, and photocopies of original scores by Ernst Bacon.
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - After Blenheim, Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; 4 p. (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Air, Photocopy of holograph piano/vocal score; 4 p.; last song (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Aliens, Holograph score in ink for narrator and ensemble; 7 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 7/2a)
  - Aliens, Holograph score in ink with part; 19 p.; Revised 1956 version (Box-folder 7/2b)
  - [Allegro], Holograph score in ink for guitar; 1 p. (Box-folder 7/3)
  - Along unpaved roads: Songs of a lonesome people [S.l.]: Delkas Music Publishing Company, 1944., Piano-vocal score; 18 p.; 2 copies (Box-folder 1/2)
  - American hymns, Holograph instrumental and vocal parts in ink; 27 p. (Box-folder 7/4)
  - American hymns, Photocopy of holograph parts; 98 p.; No complete score (Box-folder 7/4)
  - Ancestors (menuet) see: Little girl walking to school
  - Ancient Christmas carol, Photocopy of music, piano-vocal score; 2 p. (Box-folder 1/3)
  - The ark, Holograph full score in ink; 92 p.; incomplete; missing p. 2,17 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Auxerre, Photocopy of holograph piano; 2 p. (Box-folder 1/4)
  - The barnyard, Holograph score in ink; 18 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 7/6)
  - The barnyard, Photocopy of holograph; 17 p.; [bound, complete (Box-folder 7/7)
  - The barnyard, Photocopy of holograph; 9 p.; unbound, incomplete (Box-folder 7/8)
  - The bat, Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; 6 p. (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Bearwalla, Holograph score in ink; 20 p. (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Billy in the darbies, Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; 12 p. (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Bird talk [S.l.]: Summy-Birchard Publishing Company, 1957., Piano-vocal score; 4 p.; 2 copies (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Birds [S.l.]: Rongwen Music, Inc., 1955., Piano-vocal score; 3 p.; 2 copies (Box-folder 1/9)
  - [Blue Ontario], Holograph vocal score; 26 p.; Note: with typed photocopy of lyric sheets (Box-folder 1/10)
  - [Blue Ontario], Holograph piano-vocal score; 21 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 1/11)
  - [Blue Ontario], Holograph full score, earlier form; 8 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 1/12)
  - [Blue Ontario], Holograph piano-vocal fragments; 18 p. (Box-folder 1/13)
  - [Blue Ontario], Holograph instrumental parts (Box-folder 1/14)
  - [Blue Ontario], Copyist ms. of baritone and bass solo parts #2,3,10; 3 p. (Box-folder 1/15)
  - [Blue Ontario], Photocopy of holograph, piano-vocal score; 46 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 1/16)
  - [Blue Ontario], Photocopy of holograph vocal score, bound; 26 p. (Box-folder 1/17)
  - Blue Ontario, Holograph full orchestra score in ink; 108 p. (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Blue Ontario, Holograph chorus score in ink; 64 p. (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Blue Ontario, Holograph orchestra parts (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Blue Ontario, Holograph in ink, discarded sections; 22 p. (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Blue Ontario, Photocopy of holograph full orchestra score; 108 p.; 63 p.; 2 copies, one copy incomplete (Box-folder 8/5-6)
  - Blue Ontario, Photocopy of holograph, miscellaneous piano-vocal score; 22 p.; one is copied backward (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Bourée, Holograph score; 2 p.; water damaged (Box-folder 1/18)
  - The boys' choir (a ground) see: Dolly asleep (a cavatina)
  - Brady [S.l.]: Boosey Hawkes, Inc., 1949., Piano-vocal score; 7 p.; 2 copies (Box-folder 1/19)
  - The breath of life, Holograph full score for narrator and string quartet; 9 p with parts (Box-folder 1/20)
  - The breath of life, Photocopy of holograph score; 9 p with parts (Box-folder 1/21)
  - "Buffalo gals" from "Songs from the American Folk" [S.l.]: Carl Fischer, Inc., 1946., Piano-vocal score; 7 p.; 2 copies; Medium and low voice (Box-folder 1/22)
  - The buffalo skinners, Holograph score for two bassoons or cellos; [1] p. (Box-folder 1/23)
  - Buncombe county (of an afternoon), Holograph score in ink for cello and piano, 5 p. (Box-folder 1/24)
  - Burnt Cabin Branch, Holograph score in ink for flute (or oboe) and piano; 2 p. (Box-folder 1/25)
  - Burnt Cabin Branch [S.l.]: Rongwen Music, Inc., 1955., Piano score and part; 3 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 1/25)
  - The burro (small variants), Photocopy of holograph score for flute, clarinet and bassoon; 3 p. (Box-folder 1/26)
  - Buttermilk Hill [S.l]: Boosey & Hawkes, Inc., 1976., Piano-vocal score with instrumental accompaniment; 6 p.; 2 copies (Box-folder 1/27)
  - Cambiataria for guitar, Holograph score with corrections and paste over; 3 p. (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Cambiataria for guitar, Holograph score with annotations; 4 p. (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Camp meeting [S.l]: Theodore Presser Company, 1962., Piano score; 3 p.; 2 copies (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Canon, Photocopy of holograph for piano with annotations; 1 p. (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Canon [A], Holograph sketch in pencil; 6 p. (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Canon + 3rd down, canon one + 6th down, Holograph score in ink for piano; 1 leaf (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Canon de Chelly (N.M.) a chorale, Photocopy of holograph score for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Canonic duet for cellos (or bassoons), Holograph for two cellos or bassoons; 1 p. (Box-folder 9/1)
  - Canticle of the sun, Photocopy of score for 2 pianos-vocal score; 63 p. (Box-folder 2/8)
  - [Cello ensembles (easy)], Holographs in ink for 3 cellos, 2 cellos, and piano, and four cellos; 12 p. (Box-folder 9/2)
  - [Cello ensembles (easy)], Photocopy of holographs; [bound] 11 p. (Box-folder 9/2)
  - Chinquapin, N.C., Holograph score in ink for unspecified instrument with piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Christmas canon [S.l.]: Belwin-Mills Publishing Corporation, 1974., Piano-vocal score; 7 p.; 2 copies (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Christ's Sunday morn, Holograph piano-vocal score in ink; 4 p. (Box-folder 2/11)
  - A clear midnight, Photocopy of printed piano-vocal score for bass or alto; 2 p. (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Colorado, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 2 p. (Box-folder 2/13)
  - Come up from the field, father, Holograph score in ink for oboe or clarinet, horn or cello or viola, and piano; 6 p.; revised 2/15/56 (Box-folder 9/3)
  - Come up from the field, father, Holograph part for horn and oboe; 6 p.; revised 2/15/56 (Box-folder 9/3)
  - Coming and going [from Concerto for piano no.2], Photocopy of copyist's full score with holograph markings; 23 p. (Box-folder 2/14)
  - The commonplace [S.l.]: Associated Music Publishers, Inc., 1946., Piano-vocal score; 5 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 2/15)
  - [Concerto for piano no. 2], Holograph full score [bound] with copyist revisions [unbound]; 78 p. (Box-folder 18/1)
  - [Concerto for piano no. 2], Holograph drafts and revisions with some pages done in copyist's hand (Box-folder 18/2)
  - [Concerto for piano no. 2], Photocopy of holograph full score first movement [bound and unbound]; 18 p.; 2 copies (Box-folder 18/3)
  - [Concerto for piano no. 2], Photocopy of holograph full score 2nd movement with copyist revisions; 32 p.; 2 copies (Box-folder 18/4)
  - [Concerto for piano no. 2], Photocopy of holograph full score 3rd movement; 23 p.; 2nd version (Box-folder 18/5)
  - [Concerto for piano no. 2], Photocopy of holograph full score 4th movement; 78 p.; 2 copies (Box-folder 18/6)
  - Concerto [for piano] no. 2, Photocopy of holograph for 2 pianos; 112 p.; 2nd-3rd movements [2 copies] and a 4th movement (Box-folder 12/1)
  - Concerto [for piano] no. 2, Photocopy of holograph for 2 Pianos; 2nd-4th movements; revised 1982; 2 copies (Box-folder 12/2)
  - [Concerto for piano no. 3], Holograph full score in ink; 56 p. (Box-folder 17/7)
  - [Concerto for piano no. 3], Holograph Drafts; 64 p. (Box-folder 17/8)
  - [Concerto for piano no. 3], Holograph draft of the third movement in ink; 29 p. (Box-folder 17/9)
  - [Concerto grosso], Holograph score in ink for string orchestra or guitar; 40 p. (Box-folder 9/4)
  - [Concerto grosso], Photocopy of holograph with markings, bound score; 40 p. (Box-folder 9/5)
  - [Concerto grosso], Photocopy of copyist score and orchestra parts (Box-folder 9/6)
  - Constable cycle for English bells, Holograph score in ink for english bells; 21 p. (Box-folder 9/7)
  - Constable cycle for English bells, Holograph drafts in ink; p.19 (Box-folder 9/7)
  - Conversation, Photocopy of score for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 2/16)
  - The cool man (a nocturne), Holograph in ink for piano, 2 p.; On first page: set for clarinet and piano Broude, Publishers (Box-folder 2/17)
  - Coon hollow, Photocopy of holograph for guitar; 6 p. (Box-folder 2/18)
  - Copy cat (imitations), Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 2/19)
  - Corn belt, Holograph full score in ink; 87 p.; for woodwinds, brass and percussion (Box-folder 9/8)
  - Creede, (Colorado):(a chordal tones), Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 2/20)
  - Cricket, Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal; 2 p.; 2 copies (Box-folder 2/21)
  - Cullowhee, N.C. (a play-doggerel becomes a little fugue), Holograph score, in ink; 2 p.; for flute, clarinet, and bassoon (Box-folder 2/22)
  - Deep valley (folk song manner) see: Night at the opera
  - Degas: and the Paris Opera ballet, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 2 p.; a black and white study (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Destiny of the flag (for baritone or alto and chorus) see also: [To the United Nations], Holograph score in ink piano-vocal; 3 p.; (chorus may be done solo; Written at death of F.D. Roosevelt (Box-folder 2/23)
  - [Didactic piano duets], Holograph scores for piano; 5 p.; 3 pieces (Box-folder 2/24)
  - Doctor Franklin, Holograph piano-vocal score; 102 p.; Includes: 11b/3 Autograph and typewritten notes to Dr. Franklin 11a/1 Type script and lyrics with holograph annotations; [2 bound volumes] (Box-folder 11a/2-3)
  - Doctor Franklin, Holograph drafts and sketches with annotations; 39 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 11a/4)
  - Doctor Franklin, Photocopy of piano-vocal score with holograph annotations; 19 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 11a/5)
  - Doctor Franklin, Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; 236 p. (Box-folder 11a/6-7)
  - Doctor Franklin, Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; incomplete (Box-folder 11b/1-2)
  - Dolly asleep (a cavatina), Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 leaf (Box-folder 2/25)
  - Dow-del-dey-dum, Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; 1 p. (Box-folder 2/26)
  - Down yonder [S.l]: Rongwen Music, Inc., 1955., Piano-vocal score; 11 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 2/27)
  - [Drumlin legend], Holograph full score in ink; 196 p. (Box-folder 10/2)
  - [Drumlin legend], Holograph piano-vocal score in ink; 90 p. (Box-folder 10/3)
  - [Drumlin legend], Copyist's manuscripts orchestra parts (Box-folder 10/4-5)
  - The duck's dilemma, Holograph score in ink for oboe, clarinet, bassoon, and piano; 3 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 10/6)
  - Dusk, in memory of Douglas Moore, Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; 1 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 2/28)
  - Dusk over the marsh, Holograph score in ink for flute and piano; 6 p. (Box-folder 2/29)
  - Ecclesiastes: A cantata for mixed chorus and orchestra with soprano and bass solos, Holograph full score in ink; 119 p. with holograph vocal parts (Box-folder 11b/4-5)
  - Ecclesiastes: A cantata for mixed chorus and orchestra with soprano and bass solos, Holograph chorus score with piano accompaniment in ink; 42 p. (Box-folder 11b/6)
  - Ecclesiastes: A cantata for mixed chorus and orchestra with soprano and bass solos, Photocopy of holograph full score; 119.p (Box-folder 11b/7)
  - Elegy on an air of Bartolomeo Tromboncino (Venice, 1504), Holograph score in ink for strings; 8 p. (Box-folder 2/30)
  - Enchanted isle see also: Tempest, Photocopy of holograph full score; 77 p. (Box-folder 12/3)
  - Episode for guitar, Photocopy of holograph for guitar; 1 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 12/4)
  - Episodes: for recorder duos, trios, or quartets, or (upper) flute, oboe, clarinet (c), violin, (lower) bassoon, sax, cello, viola, clarinet (c), piano, Holograph full score in ink with annotations; 27 p. (Box-folder 12/5)
  - Episodes: for recorder duos, trios, or quartets, or (upper) flute, oboe, clarinet (c), violin, (lower) bassoon, sax, cello, viola, clarinet (c), piano, Photocopy of holograph score; 27 p. (Box-folder 12/6)
  - Erie Canal, Drafts; 2 leaves (Box-folder 12/7)
  - Erie Canal [S.l.]: Carl Fischer, Inc., 1942., Piano-vocal score for low voice; 7 p.; 2 copies (Box-folder 12/7)
  - Erie waters, Holograph full score in ink; 44 p. (Box-folder 11b/8)
  - Erie waters, Photocopy of holograph full score; 44 p. (Box-folder 11b/9)
  - [Fables] [2 versions], Holograph full score in ink with corrections; 75 p. (Box-folder 13/1)
  - [Fables] [2 versions], Holograph in ink for 2 pianos; 81 p. (Box-folder 13/2)
  - [Fables]: The possum and the skunk, Holograph full score in ink; 13 p. (Box-folder 13/3)
  - [Fables]: The possum and the skunk, Holograph parts; Note: some parts obsolete (Box-folder 13/3)
  - [Fables]: The possum and the skunk, Photocopy of holograph full score; 13 p. (Box-folder 13/3)
  - [Fables]: The possum and the skunk, Holograph parts; new version (Box-folder 13/4)
  - [Fables]: The possum and the skunk, Holograph string parts; old version (Box-folder 13/5)
  - [Fables]: The possum and the skunk, Photocopy of holograph for full score with markings; 33 p.; incomplete (Box-folder 13/6)
  - [Fables]: The possum and the skunk, Photocopy of holograph full score; 42 p.; old, early version (Box-folder 13/7)
  - [Fables]: Two dogs and a cow, Photocopy of holograph full score; 5 p. (Box-folder 13/8)
  - [Fables]: Two dogs and a cow, Photocopy of holograph of miscellaneous parts (Box-folder 13/9)
  - Fifty songs [S.l.]: Dragon's Teeth Press publication, 1974., Piano-vocal score; 129 p.; 2 copies (Box-folder 14a/1-2)
  - First time skating (fermati), Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 p.; skating (shifting seconds) (Box-folder 2/31)
  - A fish (a canon in symmetric inversion), Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; 2 p. (Box-folder 2/32)
  - Five poems [S.l.]: G. Schirmer, Inc., 1944., Photocopy of piano-vocal score; 11 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 2/33)
  - Flea or follow?, Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; 2 p. (Box-folder 2/34)
  - Flitericks, Holograph in ink for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 2/35)
  - The flower of night, Holograph scores for cello and piano in ink; 3 p., 4 p.; earliest dedicated to Virginia Mandyczewski (1st fiancee); 2 versions (Box-folder 14a/3)
  - Fog over Calais, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 2/36)
  - [Ford's Theater], Holograph in ink 2 piano score with clarinet, B flat trumpet, cello, and metronome; 49 p. (Box-folder 14a/4-5)
  - [Ford's Theater], Photocopy of copyist's parts (Box-folder 14a/6)
  - [Four settings], Holograph of orchestra parts with annotations (Box-folder 2/37)
  - [Four settings], Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; 6 p. each; incomplete; 2 copies (Box-folder 2/37)
  - Four songs [S.l.]: Music Press, Inc., 1946., Photocopy of printed piano-vocal score; 8 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 2/38)
  - The fox and the hens, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 3 p. (Box-folder 2/39)
  - Frog in the well, Holograph in ink for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 2/40)
  - Fugue No. 1 In American style, Photocopy of holograph for piano and bass instrument with holograph annotations; 20 p. (Box-folder 14a/7)
  - Fulfillment, Holograph for guitar; 1 p.; water damaged (Box-folder 2/41)
  - Furiante, Holograph score; 2 p. (Box-folder 2/42)
  - Garry Owen, Holograph full score in ink; 3 p. (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Gaspé, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Give me Jesus [S.l.]: Galaxy Music Corporation, 1958., Chorus score; 1 leaf each; 2 copies (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Go tell it on the mountain, Holograph of vocal score for two voices; 1 p. (Box-folder 3/4)